<Document>
  # Core Rule 7 - PvP & Combat

  In most scenarios, you should not be shooting or attacking people as soon as you see them. Where and when PvP is allowed depends on the zone you are in — see [textlink="Rule 6 - Zone Rulings" link="RuleC6Stalker"] for the full breakdown. This rule covers how combat should be conducted and what happens when you die.

  ## Fear Roleplay

  All stalkers have their limits, physically and mentally. When playing your character you must recognize immediate or impending danger — you should not constantly put your character in harm's way or ignore it in an unrealistic way. You should not be going out naked with no gear when hunting other players or simply roaming. You know the Zone is dangerous, act like it.

  In fights where you are outnumbered or overpowered, such as a 1v2 or when the enemy is significantly more geared than you, you may retreat, hide, or fight back if fired upon. At times this cannot be adequately enforced, however if you have knowledge of your opponent and go against this rule, administrative action will be taken.

  Roles like Monolith, Renegades, and Military Stalkers have more leeway on this. Monoliths are brainwashed, feel no pain, and never give up in a fight. Renegades are mentally unstable. Military Stalkers are special forces composed of veteran stalkers or specialized trained military.

  ## Safe Zone Disengagement

  You cannot enter any safe zone within 5 minutes of PvP disengagement.

  ## PvP Death Rules

  All rules from dying start from when you leave the latest safe zone (Green Zone, Faction Base). Bodies despawn after 40 minutes, leaving all gear on the ground.

  - You can remember where and how you died, but not who killed you or what faction they were from.
  - You can remember those you started traveling with, but not those you met along the way.
  - You cannot go back to your dead body until 15 minutes have passed.
  - Dying to an anomaly or mutant during a PvP fight still counts as a PvP death.
  - You cannot hint or reveal that you have died in-character to others, or where.

  ## PvE Death Rules

  - You can remember everything up until your death, but not anything after that.
  - There is no time restriction on going back to your dead body.

  Losing your stuff is tough, especially for newer players. If these rules are abused or used in bad faith, freezing in place upon seeing your corpse may be re-implemented.
</Document>
