<Document>
  # Core Rule 5 - Character & Roleplay

  ## Character Customization

  You're expected to commit to one character. You can use mirrors or the character customization menu to change hair, scars, and tattoos but you should remain recognizeable as your character. If you aren't sure about something you're always welcome to reach out to staff.

  New characters or name changes should be approved by administration before you commit to it. If you're caught changing characters without notifying staff via ahelp or a discord ticket you'll recieve a warning, repeated offences will result in a stash wipe.

  Factions with rank systems are exempt from notifying staff when changing the rank in their name (ie. Pvt John Miller to Lt John Miller).

  When making a character, do not use famous or recognizable people as your character.

  ## Roleplay Standards

  Stalker 14 is an MRP server. You are expected to be a regular human being that fits in the lore of Stalker and should avoid running around ungeared or dying on purpose. The Monolith and Renegade factions are given some leeway.

  If playing a character with major game or lore altering quirks (minor mutations, minor psionics, related to NPCs, etc...) please run it by staff first.

  Act your role. If you are a loner who just started your adventure, you are not allowed to talk about factions you haven't heard of or seen. More veteran players may share experiences they have had throughout the wipe. Roles like Ecologist, Military Stalkers, and Clear Sky are able to have a better in-depth view on the zone, anomaly types, and artifacts. Sharing meta info in LOOC such as artifact or mob stats, faction base locations, etc may result in administrative action.

  Members of a faction should always be playing as that faction, faction members caught playing as the loner role instead of their faction may face administrative action. Faction members should also strive to represent their faction to the best of their ability in most situations and are expected to follow any faction rules found in the faction rules section as well as rules set by the faction leader.
</Document>
