<Document>
  # Core Rule 9 - Robbing and Looting

  When engaging in interactions that involve robbing, kidnapping, or searching another player, you must clearly speak in English. You are allowed to use other languages in casual settings, however this is an English server. It is unfair to players who have no idea what you are asking or demanding.

  Being robbed is something you will likely encounter often, as [textlink="Bandits" link="RuleF1"] and [textlink="Renegades" link="RuleF2"] frequently patrol the Zone. These rules apply to all factions — individual factions may have additional robbing rules in their [textlink="faction pages" link="RuleC9Stalker"].

  ## General Rules

  - Nobody should be robbing Rookies of everything they have. If they have a green Rookie patch they're a new player with little to take, when engaging in antagonistic behavior with a Rookie take no more than one or two items from them. If they fight back they can be killed but shouldn't have all of their gear stripped.
  - When setting out to rob in lower tier areas like Cordon, expect to run into players who don't have much worth taking. Consider setting up checkpoints to charge a toll for passing, or seeking more creative ways of engaging with players in these areas.
  - When robbing a player, if they actively resist or make it difficult (constantly breaking restraints, trying to run, being overly uncooperative), you may put them into a critical state. However, you should use meds to revive them. If you have to revive more than twice, you are allowed to kill them — in this case, AHELPing problem behavior is encouraged. Resistance breaches the rules for Roleplay Standards, Fear Roleplay, and Suicide when captured.
  - Anyone being robbed should at least be left with enough gear to reach a safe zone without dying to mutants on the way back.
  - Robbers should NOT be using 'say' binds to rob people. You need to clearly type out that you are robbing said person. No Gmod "Drop 5k or die" binds.

  ## Zone Restrictions

  - No robbing or looting should take place in a [color=#008000]Green Zone[/color]. This includes SSD players and corpses unless permission has been explicitly given by the owner of the body.
  - You are allowed to loot dead people outside of [color=#008000]Green Zones[/color], but you are not allowed to watch someone die and then proceed to loot them. Given the opportunity, you should attempt to rescue them unless the situation is too dangerous to handle (e.g., heavily irradiated area, anomaly field with no protection, horde of dangerous mutants).

  ## Faction Gear

  Anyone caught wearing faction gear can be escalated against by warring factions using [textlink="gray zone rules" link="RuleC6Stalker"].

  Anyone can KOS a person wearing Monolith gear (excluding weapons) outside of green and gray zones.

  ## Who Can Rob

  Factions that are hostile to each other are allowed to rob one another. In this scenario you should follow the same rules as Bandit robbing rules.

  Loners are only allowed to rob people when accompanied by [textlink="Bandits" link="RuleF1"] or [textlink="Renegades" link="RuleF2"].
</Document>
