<Document>

# Loadout System

Save your gear setup and re-equip quickly after death or when switching roles.

[color=#FFD700][bold]This feature is in beta. There is a small possibility of losing items.[/bold][/color]

## Quick Save / Quick Load

The fastest way to save and restore your equipment.

[bullet] [bold]Quick Save[/bold] - Saves everything you're currently wearing

[bullet] [bold]Quick Load[/bold] - Re-equips your quick-saved gear from your stash

Perfect for getting back into the Zone fast after respawning. Update it whenever you upgrade your gear.

## Named Loadouts

Create multiple saved loadouts for different situations:

[bullet] A combat loadout with heavy armor and weapons

[bullet] A stealth loadout with light gear for artifact hunting

[bullet] A trading loadout with extra carrying capacity

Enter a name (up to 32 characters) and click [bold]Save New[/bold]. Your loadouts persist between sessions.

## What Gets Saved

[bullet] All equipped clothing and armor

[bullet] Weapons and their attachments

[bullet] Magazines with their current ammo count

[bullet] Items in your backpack, vest, and pockets

[bullet] Items inside containers (nested up to 5 levels deep)

## What Does NOT Get Saved

[bullet] Items held in your hands

[bullet] Your ID card / PDA

[bullet] Implants and organs

## Preview

Click any loadout to see a preview showing exactly what items will be equipped. You can rotate the preview to inspect your gear from all angles.

## Missing Items

If items from your loadout aren't available, they're marked as [color=#FF6B6B]missing[/color]. The preview panel shows which items you need to find.

[bold]You can still load a partial loadout[/bold] - available items will be equipped and missing items will be skipped.

## How Loading Works

When you load a loadout:

[bullet] Items you're wearing that match the loadout stay equipped

[bullet] Items you're wearing that aren't in the loadout go to your stash

[bullet] Loadout items are retrieved from your stash and equipped

[italic]Good hunting, stalker.[/italic]

</Document>
